<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | The Works of Sandra Fogg</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maricultura Planning Tool</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My peers and I built an interactive Shiny application that can guide planning efforts for aquaculture development. First, we defined input and output parameters for the app. Then, we integrated these parameters to our three suitability models (site suitability, productivity, and profitability). The interface of the app was created with Shiny using R version 3.6.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inputs
All the constraints used in the site suitability analysis were transformed into inputs that can be modified by the app users, as well as the life history parameters in the productivity assessment, and the costs in the profitability assessment.  The app will run all the suitability models based on the inputs provided by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outputs
The main outputs created by the app are three maps, one for each model. The site suitability map shows parcels identified as suitable for aquaculture, the productivity map shows biomass (MT/cell), and the profitability map shows profits (USD/cell). All maps can be downloaded in TIFF grid format for further analysis. Two additional outputs are a total suitable area chart and percentage exclusion chart.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snowshoe Hares LTER</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-project-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project exercised skills in data wrangling and visualization. The original data frame required name changes, cleaning of columns, and omission of incomplete or inadequate data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See PDF for Analysis and Results&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steelhead Trout Passage</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-project-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exercise was a great introduction to time-series data analysis. It involved lots of wrangling to transform the sampling dates into the appropriate format for analysis. It also utilized data visualization skills to best intepret and present the long-term data set for adult steelhead passage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See PDF for Analysis and Results&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Climate PCA</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-project-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I learned how to perform principle components analysis for this task.  Data first required wrangling and cleaning, and then I had to choose which variables of the provided data set that I wanted to perform PCA with. It was helpful to visualize the relationship between variables and where covariance might occur within a model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See PDF for Analysis and Results&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
